NGUYEN TIEN LONG

GAME DEVELOPER

Looking forward to gaining experience in a professional environment as a game developer at Company. The target is to master technical skills at work as well as master specialized skills in game development on many platforms that can help me expand my knowledge. Completing the task of a Game Developer and contributing to the development of the company

Contact

github.com/BuCiuPi



linkedin.com/in/nguyenlong147



nguyentienlong147@gmail.com

Porfolio https://buciupi.github.io/

Skill

Language

+84-397-475-616

C/C++/C# HTML JavaScript Java Assembly TypeScript

Shading Language

ShaderLab HLSL Shader Graph GLSL CSS

IDE & Engine

Unity Unreal Engine UEFN Directx 11 OnpenGL VS Code Visual Studio

Tool

Git GithubProject BitBucket Gitlab Trello Notion

Blender PhotoShop Offices Davinci Resolve

Principle

OOP Game DesignPatterns KISS DRY SOLID YAGNI

Experience

Junior Game Developer - INDI GAMES

Jun 2022 - Apr 2024

Full-time: On-Site: Ho Chi Minh City

- Developed games using the Unity Engine.
- Designed game shaders, utilizing ShaderGraph, ShaderLab, HLSL, and GLSL.
- · Wrote Unity Editor tools, including data import, level design, game data management, testing, and debugging.
- Expand gameplay and port existing projects from Mobile and PC to WebGL.
- Collaborated with a Game Designer to customize game levels and improve gameplay.
- Created games using both Unreal Engine 5 and Unreal Engine for Fortnite using Verse.

Trainee Game Developer - INDI GAMES

Apr 2022 - Jul 2022

Full-time: On-Site: Ho Chi Minh City

- Gained expertise in the entire game development lifecycle, from pre-production to post-production.
- Utilized Git, GitHub, and GitLab for seamless team collaboration.
- Developed mini-games using Unity Learn to hone skills.
- Engaged in game development training courses.

Project

Match 3 Game - Unity Engine

Puzzle, Casual

https://buciupi.github.io/match3-game-build/

Match 3 games involve swapping adjacent tiles to create lines of three or more identical pieces. As you match these tiles, they disappear, allowing new ones to fall into place.

- Designed a Scalable Game System for creating new types of gameplay.
- Designed an Effect Manager System based on an object pooling pattern to efficiently manage multiple object pools within the scene.
- Created various visual effects for the game, using a particle system, animator controller, skinned sprite renderer, sprite rigging, and transition animations.
- Implemented Unity Editor tools for tasks such as data import, level design, game data management, testing, and debugging.
- Collaborated closely with a Game Designer and 2D artists to customize game levels and enhance overall gameplay.

Shader - Unity Engine

https://www.behance.net/gallery/205082547/Unity-Shader

- Shader Effects in Unity Engine: VFX Graph, Particle System, Shell shading, Toon shading, Pixelation shader
- Shader Tools: Shader Graph, ShaderLab, GLSL, HLSL

Shader, Custom material - Unreal Engine

https://www.behance.net/gallery/210400295/UE5-Shader-Custom-material

- Shader and Custom Material Techniques: Vertex displacement, Texture packing, Interior mapping, Toon shading, Tessellation
- Post Processing Effects: Blur, Color filtering, Underwater effect, Lens masking

Render Pipeline, Computer Graphics, Shader - DirectX 11

https://www.behance.net/gallery/210403657/Direct-11-Render-Pipeline-HLSL

- Rendering Pipeline: Forward rendering, Deferred rendering, PBR lighting
- Shader (HLSL): Vertex shader, Compute shader, Geometry shader, Pixel shader, Tessellation shader
- **Techniques:** Vertex displacement, Texture packing, Basic lighting, Terrain rendering, GPU instancing, Occlusion culling, Stencil buffer, Billboard rendering
- Post Processing: Blur, Ambient Occlusion, SSAO (Screen Space Ambient Occlusion)

Education

Bachelor of Software Engineering

HO CHI MINH CITY UNIVERSITY OF TECHNOLOGY - HUTECH

GPA: 3.26/4 2018-2023

Certifications

■ GAMELOFT GAME JAM 2020 CERTIFICATE OF PARTICIPATION